'It's believed
that time stops for no one.'
'That's right.'
'Although time doesn't stop,
it can definitely change.'
'And those who have
the skill to change it'
'are visionaries.'
'They're always
one step ahead of time.'
'This is a story about people'
'whose dreams and vision'
'connected with countless wrists
across India.'
Everyone warned me
about this decision,
but I listened to no one.
Now our company
will be shut down.
This happened because of me.
I'm sorry.
It's over.
- An embodiment of hard work!
- Is the definition of a labourer!
- If you want us to work...
- Take care of us!
- An embodiment of hard work!
- Is the definition of a labourer!
- If you want us to work...
- Take care of us!
An embodiment of hard work!
- Is the definition of a labourer!
- If you want us to work...
- Take care of us!
- An embodiment of hard work!
- Is the definition of a labourer!
If you want us to work...
Where is Mr. Desai?
If this continues, the Vashi Bridge
won’t be completed
for a few more years.
Why are you worrying?
Let's find new workers.
I'm sorry, sir,
but changing the bottle
doesn't turn water into juice.
What if the new workers
demand the same things?
No! No! No!
We cannot afford that.
Exactly!
Where the hell is Desai?
If you want us to work...
- Take care of us!
- Excuse me.
They say, "An empty stomach
can't pray." Have you heard that?
Likewise,
you can't soften hard-hearted people
by getting wet.
- What?
- Yes, it's true.
The people sitting inside
don't care about you
getting wet in the rain.
However,
if these developers fall sick,
who will protest tomorrow?
Take an umbrella and then shout.
Don't move
until your demands are fulfilled!
- If you want us to work...
- Take care of us!
Just a second. Sorry!
Please change the slogan.
- Excuse me! - This sounds
more like a Salim-Javed dialogue.
Okay.
- The embodiment of hard work...
- No! No! No!
This... Uh...
- Your slogan describes you.
- Yes.
Not your demands.
Speak about your demands.
And...
Please speak in English.
They 'think' in Hindi,
but like to listen to English.
But we can't speak English.
Right?
Right, my friends?
- You discard!
- We work hard!
- Chin up!
- Pay up!
Huh!
Now they've started
protesting in English.
Who taught them English?
I did, sir.
Mr. Desai?
Present!
I'm sorry. I'm late, sir.
I was hunting for umbrellas.
They had been getting drenched
in the rain for the past two days.
Wow!
We are praying
that they stop protesting
because of the rain,
and you're giving them umbrellas!
My wife always says that,
between people and process,
you should choose people,
because they execute the process.
Whose side are you on?
I'm the project manager.
I don't take sides.
I see everyone as equal.
"Saamaan?"
'Saamaan'.
No good?
Sorry, I'm trying
to improve my Hindi.
Equalise means 'saamaan'.
- 'Samaan'!
I treat them as equals.
Huh? Good?
Please tell me.
What exactly is their problem?
The problem is that
the workers work for 12 hours,
but want to be paid for 18.
Not exactly.
They work every day for 12 hours,
and travel for 6 hours.
It takes them 3 hours to get here
and 3 hours to return.
That means they give us 18 hours
out of the 24 in a day.
And before they can
even rest after getting home,
they start planning
for the next day.
- So, try to put yourselves
in their shoes. - Look.
These workers don't come here
on foot. They come by bus.
They can sleep peacefully
while travelling.
I have a solution.
Please explain.
Let's go for a walk.
A walk?
Yes. Certain things
are understood through demonstration
rather than discussion.
Come on, let's go.
Okay! Let's go.
You will need your umbrellas.
- We work hard!
- You discard!
Gosh! How much more?
- Mr. Tiwari.
- Yes?
This is your apartment, right?
Right.
Could you please open it?
Nice!
Very nice!
It's spacious.
Six people can easily fit in here.
The next one is 102.
That's mine, Desai.
Right, and there are
six more over there.
What is your point, Desai?
We'll have to vacate this place.
- What?
- Do we have to vacate?
- What are you saying?
If we want to stop this strike
and complete
the Vashi Bridge on time,
this is the only solution.
We'll all leave, and our developers,
whom you call workers,
will move in here.
Right?
where will we go?
- We'll move back into our houses.
- Huh!
I will travel from Bombay,
and you can travel from Pune.
Desai, we live
four to five hours away from here.
So how are we supposed to travel
back and forth every day?
Peacefully.
I understand
what you're trying to say, Desai,
but that is not possible.
If you have another solution,
please tell me.
Let's go for a walk.
Again!
If I had known,
I would have worn my sports shoes.
Why have we come
to the Marketing Building?
- Akash.
- Hmm?
What is the area of this hall?
Approximately 1,400 to 1,500 sq ft.
"1,500 sq ft."
If we build
wooden partitions
in these three places,
we can have five rooms, right?
- Hmm.
- How many such halls do we have?
There are ten halls
and two vacant floors.
So that's 20 halls,
with five rooms each.
Which gives us...
100 rooms.
Nothing escapes you, sir.
Our skilled developers
can stay here.
We will need the Marketing Head's
permission for this.
We will have to convince everyone
and obtain their signatures.
It's a long and tricky process.
It's not that tricky, sir.
Everyone has already signed,
and only yours is pending.
I need to discuss this
with the board.
Please, sir.
Oi.
If you already knew
about this place,
why did you
take them to the quarters?
I had to show them the bitter gourd
to convince them to eat the okra.
How could you?
Anyway, I'm quite impressed.
- Hmm?
- Hmm.
But, Zee, they haven't agreed yet.
Um, the workers...
I'm sorry, you're being too nice
to the developers.
Really.
Uh, please.
Please talk to them.
I would love to,
but I don't belong to NBIDC.
- It's fine. I'll take care of it.
- Okay.
- Thank you, Akash.
- Good luck!
Thank you, sir.
- Desai.
- Yes.
That was good.
I'm thankful to have
borrowed you from Tata.
Desai, I was thinking
that every time we reached
a dead end in this project,
you sought solutions for us.
I think you deserve much more.
More money, better policies,
and a secure future.
One should at least have a
permanent job in this fleeting life.
So,
will you join NBIDC?
Permanently?
Come with me.
Are you shocked or surprised?
Sir, NBIDC is an incredible place,
but the Tatas have sent me here
on a five-year lease...
I mean, I was lent to you.
Today is the last day
of that contract.
I know. That's why I'm asking you
to join us.
I'll get you promoted
in a few years.
Desai.
Thousands apply for this job
and sit exams for years,
yet they never make it here.
I believe those people
deserve this job, sir.
What does Tata offer you
that NBIDC cannot?
Peace.
A person feels at peace
with their family.
And Tata is family to me.
A talented man like you
should work for the country.
That's exactly what I
intend to do, sir.
Thank you for your kind offer.
Sir!
The developers have agreed.
Uh, they're bloody workers,
for God's sake.
They agreed, but you didn't.
Obviously!
Please don't start your Hindi
classes in front of Rajini.
She won't put up with you like I do.
Are you jealous of Rajini?
Do you want to marry me?
You're not that lucky now.
- I have my Kumud.
- Ooh!
A heartbreak!
But I'm so happy for you, Zee.
Will you forget me?
Akash, of course I will forget you.
I'm not good
at long-distance relationships.
Should I crash somewhere? Should I?
Thank you!
Argh!
My pleasure!
What happened?
Someone once said
we'd change the times together.
Sounds familiar.
But, sir, you're changing
the destination itself.
"There's no destination in sight,
not even a trace of it."
"Yet our journey continues."
You said this quote without
referring to the Hindi dictionary!
- Will you join Tata?
- Really?
Are you serious?
Zee!
Answer me!
Ta-ta!
"My heart is restless."
"I don't know who it will fall for."
Did you leave the job?
Yes, I did.
Really?
What should I call you now?
Mr. Desai or Professor Desai?
Are you joining the Tatas again?
I thought you didn't want to work
in the corporate world anymore.
I thought you wanted to fulfil your
dream of becoming a professor.
Was that my dream?
For that, you need
to understand yourself first.
Only then can you
understand your dream.
Ah, my guru!
Here's your honorarium.
How's the 'akuri'?
"My heart is..."
'- Mom!
- Mama!'
Dad!
My love!
- Uh... Here you are!
- Ah!
Wow, Mom! We have a guest today.
Does a guest come
to your house and cook? Huh?
A paying guest.
"A paying guest?"
Very smart.
- Come here.
- No! No! No!
Come here!
Now, you won't have to travel
four hours to see me.
So, you're finally becoming
a professor?
Um...
Tomorrow, I will take
a day off from school.
- We'll go out to play.
- That's a good idea.
- Yes.
- Listen up, hero!
You go to school, not an office,
where you can take a day off.
Your dad will be busy from tomorrow.
Why? Where are you going?
To meet his second family.
Bye! Bye! Bye! Mwah! Bye!
- Dad, your lunchbox!
- "Lunchbox!" Yes.
- Oh! "Lunchbox!"
My lunchbox. Thank you!
Good morning! Good morning!
Where to?
Office!
- I know that, but who are you?
- Xerxes.
What does that mean?
It's a name. That's my name.
It seems really old.
Were you on holiday?
Yes, a five-year-long holiday.
Come in.
Pinks!
Desai!
I've been expecting you.
Ah! The burden of expectations.
- Pinks.
- Hmm?
Who has occupied my office?
Ask Jeh about it.
Only he can tell you that.
Come with me.
But, Pinks...
Don't call me that.
Only Mr. Tata can call me that.
Okay, but where is he?
- On a business trip.
- Oh.
- He will be back today.
- Oh!
This is your 'destination'.
Oh!
Do you need anything? Tea or coffee?
I want my cabin back.
You can't have it.
At least give me some work.
Please...
Will you give me a chance
- to help you?
- No.
Thank you.
Um...
Hello!
Sir, I have the sheets with me.
Yes, sir. I have the numbers.
We can start tallying them
right away, sir.
Yes, sir. Yes, absolutely.
Correspondence.
It's not 'correspondance'. Right?
Please mop at the corners. Okay?
Do it properly.
'Avsar' means opportunity.
Sir, over here. Mr. Khanna.
Over there as well.
Yes, sir!
I wanted to discuss with you...
There are plenty
of grammatical errors.
Shall I retype it?
No, thank you.
- Sir.
- Yes?
Where is Pinks?
I think she went to meet Mr. Tata.
Where?
There he is, 001.
I have heard of 007,
but what's 001?
It's Jeh's licence number.
He is the first Indian
to get a pilot's licence.
And he still flies himself.
Incredible!
Oh! My entire staff is here
as a welcome committee.
- Ahuja Sahib.
- Welcome, sir.
How are you?
- Hello, Mr. Singh.
- Welcome, sir.
- [in Gujarati] Zee, how are you?
- I'm great.
This is Mr. Jim Edgar.
Greetings!
He works with the great
Martin Cooper.
He had to come to India
for work, so I gave him a lift.
In return, he gave me the chance
to show you this prototype.
This is the genius of Martin Cooper.
A totally wireless cellphone.
Have a look.
Mr. Tata, I know
this is a dream come true, but...
Who will buy a cellphone?
Only the wealthy.
No, sir.
No.
Innovation is always expensive,
but by the time it reaches
the distribution stage,
it becomes affordable.
- Right.
- Yes.
For example, the car, the radio,
the gramophone, or the telephone.
In the beginning, all of these
were extremely expensive.
But look now.
Oi, Pinks,
'vishishtata' is expensive,
but 'samaveshta' is affordable.
What does that mean?
What he means is that
exclusivity is expensive,
and inclusivity is affordable!
Yes!
Thank you!
Here you are. Thank you, Jim.
Thank you, sir.
There's a car waiting for you.
- Thank you.
- I'll see you later.
- Thank you, sir!
- Bye.
Sir.
We already have
a telephone in the market,
so what's the need
for a wireless phone?
Ahuja Sahib.
Yes, sir.
Do you remember when, last year,
you had a multi-million dollar deal
to negotiate?
- Of course, sir.
- And you
needed my permission for that.
An urgent permission.
Of course, sir. Of course.
It was a deal worth millions.
- How could I forget that?
- Right.
I was on a one-week tour back then,
and since my schedule was
confidential, you couldn't reach me.
Right! That's right.
Now suppose I were
carrying a telephone with me,
neither of us would be
constrained by wires.
No deal would have slipped
through your fingers.
Mr. Tata,
do you think we should enter
the cellphone business?
Investing in any new innovation
is risky,
but we can certainly
draw inspiration from it.
But remember,
having passion isn't enough.
You must have an idea
that is feasible.
That's all.
Thanks.
Sir...
Sir, I want to speak with you.
- Get in!
- Okay.
What have they done
to you at NBIDC, Zee?
I'm not pathetic
because of NBIDC, sir,
but because of you.
Why? What did I do?
You know how much I love my job.
Yet you sent me there
and found my replacement here.
Only because of your experience.
It was time for you
to get a promotion.
"Promotion?" I sit around
doing nothing all day.
Who works
on the very first day of a job?
Please rest for a while.
I need something exciting.
I want a challenge.
- Really?
- Hmm.
Well, you're in luck.
Because a challenge has been
waiting for you for a long time.
Okay.
The Tata Press.
"The Tata Press?"
It has been making a loss
for seven years.
You said you wanted a challenge.
This is not a challenge.
This is a death sentence.
Zee, this is
the most precious watch
in the world.
It's a rare edition.
Henry Andre,
the owner of Andre Jeuba,
presented me with this watch.
It's very dear to me.
If you find a way
to recover Tata Press's losses,
it'll be yours.
Do you accept the challenge?
- Good morning, my darlings.
- Good morning!
It's for you!
Thank you.
Shall I drop you two off at school?
- Yes, Dad.
- Come on, let's go.
- Keep your plates in the sink.
- Yes.
Wait... Hang on!
Hmm! Where is...
- Somebody is excited.
- Let's go, Dad.
Somebody has a new challenge.
Come on, let's go.
Oh, my!
Do you think
you'll be able to defeat me?
Let's see.
- Excuse me!
- Yes?
Who's in charge here?
Mr. Mody?
You must be Mr. Desai.
Yes.
- Welcome!
- Thank you.
Just a minute.
Varun, please bring me
two cups of Rajwadi tea. Yes.
Come with me, Mr. Desai.
Let me give you a tour of the press.
No. I need all the press files.
All the files?
All the files.
Oops.
May I sit here?
Uh, yes.
Zee.
It's 1 a.m. Come and sleep inside.
Just two minutes.
Wrap it up quickly.
Thank you!
I need the sales report
for the last five years.
This is for the financial year
1978-79.
'Tata Press gave Xerxes
sleepless nights,'
'but he didn't know'
'that in resurrecting it,'
'he would discover a dream'
'that would
keep him awake day and night.'
Varun, please bring us Rajwadi Tea!
- Morning... Morning! Good morning!
- Good morning.
It might be a good morning for you.
What is this Indus Script project?
The most money was spent
on this project last year.
The officials
from the Archaeological Department
found some old scripts.
They wanted
to preserve those scripts,
and we wanted to save
the press's reputation.
So, we took on the project.
But why did we incur so much loss?
Actually, what happened
was that, to print those scripts,
we needed
new machines and new fonts.
I thought Mr. Manoharan
would keep bringing in new projects,
and our press's profits
would increase.
Is he Shankar Manoharan?
Yes! But unfortunately,
it was his last project.
After that, we never saw him again.
Hello, Operator.
Please connect me to the Delhi
Archaeological Department.
Hello! Is it the Delhi
Archaeological Department?
Could I speak
to Mr. Shankar Manoharan?
Transferred?
Hello, Operator.
Could you please connect me
to the Delhi Traffic Department?
Thank you.
Hello! Yes. Could I speak
to Mr. Shankar Manoharan, please?
Transferred!
Operator, could you please
connect me to TIDCO in Madras?
Hello, TIDCO? Yes.
[in Hindi] Yes! May I speak...
Could I please speak
to Mr. Shankar Manoharan?
"Bombay?"
Thank you.
Do you realise how much...
Where are my noodles?
"Noodles?"
Yes, I ordered it.
You're the manager, right?
Yes, I'm the manager.
So where are my noodles?
I ordered it an hour ago.
We took the order a year ago.
Yet we haven't received
a single order since.
Sorry?
I'm Tata Press's general manager,
not the hotel's.
Oh!
Oh my God!
Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you. I'm Xerxes.
- Shankar.
- Oh.
Do you realise
how much money you've cost us?
May I wear my clothes first?
Actually,
I don't hold meetings in a bathrobe.
This is archaeological work, Xerxes.
We don't necessarily
find something every month.
I agree, but what about
our business relations?
You...
You were the last hope of the press.
You don't know how much money...
Why are you taking out
your frustration on me?
Do you think
I enjoyed searching
for ancient stones
for the Archaeological Department?
I thought
history was your passion.
I like working
for our country's progress,
not for history.
Ditto.
Getting transferred
to the Archaeology Department
was not my wish.
It was a punishment.
- "Punishment?"
- Yes.
But why?
In my previous posting,
I used to deal with smugglers.
Why are you staring at me?
It's true.
- "Smugglers?"
- Hmm.
However, I made a mistake.
I confiscated the goods
of some shady people,
and pressure from my superiors
led to my demotion.
What did you confiscate?
You cannot even imagine.
Booze?
Your imagination is far too limited.
Diamonds?
Gold? Drugs?
- You can't guess.
- Wood?
Animal skins?
- Toothbrushes? - You'll be
saying "gallstones" next.
- Human organs.
- Please stop it.
Watches.
"Watches?"
Imported foreign watches.
Everyone wants to wear them,
but not everyone can afford them.
Because these watches
don't just show the time,
they display the status
of the person wearing them.
That's why watches are the most
smuggled item in our country.
Its demand
will never decrease. Mind it.
Never.
Ashok!
Sharma!
- Varun!
- Yes, sir!
Has everyone gone deaf?
Why can't I see anyone?
Where's everyone?
Sir, everyone has gone out!
'Attention! Attention! Attention!'
'Ladies and gentlemen,'
'five sarees for just 50 rupees!'
'Sale! Sale! Sale!'
The rates will increase
during the festive season.
That is for 300.
This one is for 400,
but it's the latest design.
- It'll look really good on
your wrist. - Mister, show me this.
- Yes, sir. Let me show you the
latest design. - I'll give Rs. 300.
- Mister.
- Yes.
How much for this?
This is for 800.
Please wait, ma'am.
I'll give your watch. Here it is.
It's too expensive.
It's a watch, not soap.
There is a fixed rate.
We don't bargain. The rates
will rise during the festival.
So, buy now.
The watches are really nice.
Where do you get them from?
Why are you wasting
my time, my friend?
If you want it, buy it.
If not, just leave.
Mister, what kind
of watches do you have?
Sir, just tell me
which watch you want.
We have all the watches.
Citizen, Seiko, Roamer, and Sandoz.
Is this watch in demand?
- Riyaz, please deal with him.
- Okay.
- Please leave. Come on, leave.
- This one...
What's your turnover?
"Turn?" What do you mean?
I mean, how much
do you earn in a day?
Sonu, please deal with him.
They threw me out, sir.
Hello, Operator.
Could you please connect me
to the New Bombay NBIDC office?
'Done?'
'It's the best.'
Mister, I need a watch.
- Which company?
- Swiss.
You'll get it here.
I need forty thousand watches.
Forty thousand?
I want to give those
as Diwali gifts to my employees.
Listen,
I can only give you 40 watches.
No problem. Thank you.
Psst!
I can get you the watches.
You?
Why are you joking? Let it be.
I'm not joking.
I have some good connections.
Do you run a company?
I have an arrangement
with the supplier.
Please come
to this address at 9 p.m.
Don't bring the police with you.
Otherwise, it will backfire.
Be there on time.
Is this the right place?
Yes, I think so.
- Your name, please?
- Akash Dixit.
- Do you both have the same name?
- No.
I'm Xerxes Desai.
Hello, sir.
Akash Dixit.
'Xerox' Desai.
- Xerxes...
- Sir, it's Xerxes.
'Zer-ka-sis', Xerxes.
Sorry.
How many do you want?
Sir, can we see the options?
All right.
Sir, this one.
This one and this one. All four.
Ten units of each brand.
So, all in all, it comes to 40,000.
"40,000?"
Yes, sir.
Why do you need 40,000 watches?
- We should leave.
- No, let me talk to him.
He is a gangster.
What are you whispering
to each other?
Sir, um...
Sir, we want to start
a small watch business.
Selling vests and underwear
could make a small business,
but trading in watches
could prove expensive.
The watch business
is my biggest business.
How big, sir?
I mean,
what is your annual turnover?
- No, sir...
- Are you an informant?
No, we really want
to start a watch business.
You know, Mumbai's artists,
politicians making
statements in Parliament,
big businessmen, advocates,
engineers, and doctors.
They all wear my watches.
Absolutely, sir.
If you dare meddle in my business,
your delicate wrists
won't even be able to carry bangles.
- No, sir. I was just...
- Uh...
We won't meddle.
- It's cancelled.
- We're sorry, sir.
- Thank you, sir.
- Sorry!
Idiots.
Come on, fast!
- I hope we're not being followed.
- You messed up.
"Forty thousand!"
So, what's my role in this job?
What's my salary,
and where's my cabin?
Did you leave your job?
Yes...
Since you asked me to come, I came.
No! No! No! I only asked
for a one-off favour.
I didn't ask you to quit your job.
- Huh?
- Yes.
I...
I mean... Attitude...
- No! No!
- What should I do now?
- Hear me out.
- What will I do now?
Listen to me.
I don't even have Jeh's confirmation
for the watch project.
- Huh...
- But if it's confirmed,
then you're hired.
Otherwise, you can rejoin NBIDC.
Do you even know what I did there?
'You will regret this.'
'It's fine. I'll deal with it.'
'I have zero interest
in your government job.'
'All the best.'
[in Spanish] 'Hasta la vista.'
'Oh!'
"Hasta la vista?"
Oh, no.
How will I face Dad,
Vihaan, and Kumud?
Please don't panic.
What do you mean?
When you didn't even have
the basic confirmation,
why did you ask me to come?
- I want the confirmation right now.
Come with me. - Oi!
- Come on.
- One second, please.
The pitch is not ready.
- It's not ready.
- Prepare it there.
- Come with me immediately.
- Okay.
Let me just confirm if he's there.
Take Mr. J.R.D.'s confirmation.
Enough is enough.
Okay.
Hello, Operator.
Yes. Bombay House, please.
Yes. May I speak to Mr. Tata?
Oi, Pinks! Yes, I'm good.
How are you...
Um, may I speak to J.R.D., please?
Hi, Jeh!
Jeh, I want to meet you.
Zee, I'm leaving for Europe tonight.
'I'll call you once I get there.'
No, it's really important.
- Let's go.
- Okay! Okay!
Hey...
All the best.
Yes, thank you.
- Give me a second, sir.
- Hi, Jeh!
Make it quick.
Tata Press cannot become profitable.
So you're giving up the challenge.
No! The challenge was
to rescue the press from losses.
It wasn't about
making it profitable.
Don't play with words.
Get to the point.
Jeh, there are only two ways
to make the press profitable.
One is an IPO.
But where would we invest
the funds raised from the public?
Will we buy more useless machines?
What's the second option?
Do you know about Nokia?
Are you talking
about the paper mill?
Not anymore.
They're pivoting
to the cellphone business.
Good for them. So?
I also want to pivot away
from Tata Press.
Just because Nokia is pivoting, it
doesn't mean we would do the same.
I'm not copying them, Jeh.
I went through and researched
all the files from the press.
There's no scope.
Press is a thing of the past.
And what is the trend?
- Watches?
- Yes!
- Come on! You cannot be serious.
- I am!
Listen, watchmaking
is a difficult
and delicate business.
You won't be able to do it.
- So...
- Please hear me out.
Please give me two minutes, Jeh.
You have one minute.
And your time starts now.
Okay! You and the Tatas
launched Lakmé
for the women of this country.
A brand that changed
the way women see themselves.
Lakmé was launched
for the country's 'Lakshmi',
but what about the 'Narayanas'?
There's no accessory
that represents their personality,
status, and achievements.
The one thing that can represent
all of those things is a wristwatch.
Not a single premium watch
has ever been made in India.
I want to make it.
I don't want to make it just for
film stars, doctors, and lawyers,
but for the common people of India.
We'll make watches
not only for those
who have good times,
but also for those
who want to change their times.
We are the best candidates
to do this, Jeh.
- We can do this, and we must!
- And your one minute is over.
I don't know about the watch,
but your Hindi
has definitely improved.
Jeh.
Think about it.
I don't know.
I really don't know.
- Good morning, sir.
- Good morning.
What's my schedule
for tomorrow and the day after?
Tomorrow is a day off, sir.
- Hmm. - We'll meet the dealers
the day after tomorrow.
So please arrange my meeting
with the chairman
of Andre Jeuba for tomorrow.
But he's in Switzerland.
I know.
I'll prepare the proposal letter
and schedule the meeting.
- Right.
- Yes, sir.
Mr. Tata.
Come with me, Pinks.
This way, please.
[speaking French]
Sir has read your proposal.
Are the Indians
really thinking
of making world-class watches?
Absolutely.
That's why
we want to collaborate
with the world's finest watchmakers,
Andre Jeuba.
You know... In fact, your father
presented me with this one.
We are making
the best watches in the world
because we never compromise
on quality.
Right.
Look at this mechanism.
[speaking French]
Mr. Tata,
Indian engineers know
how to make watches,
but will they be able
to make world-class watches?
See, we choose the best components
from all over the world
and assemble them
precisely in the watch.
That's how we make
300 world-class watches every day.
We produce a limited number
of watches, Mr. Tata,
each with a precision
of five seconds.
Can Indians really manufacture
world-class watches?
[speaking French]
We believe your answer
to all our questions is "no".
Then why should we collaborate
with an Indian company?
With all due respect, Mr. Tata,
Indians don't know
how to manufacture watches.
They lack talent and skill.
They can only labour.
Watches require skill.
We can drink together.
I can offer you
the finest Swiss chocolate today,
but not a deal.
The designer of your best-selling
watches, Sita Meyer, is an Indian.
Yet you doubt
the capabilities of Indians.
I am 100% confident
we can make a world-class watch.
We manufacture locomotives,
steel plants, communication systems,
and even aeroplanes,
but your company doesn't.
That's because your thinking
is small and constricted,
just like your watches.
[in French]
Thank you for the chocolate
and for your time.
Please translate everything
I've just said for him.
I've been lying and coming here
for the past few days.
I made a serious mistake
by leaving NBIDC.
I want to go back to New Bombay.
Then please go. Leave.
You keep whinging all the time.
Anyway, you're losing.
Don't use big English words
and infuriate me.
I'm telling you. Or...
Sir!
Are you certain
you can make a watch?
Jeh, what brings you here?
I asked you a question.
Can you make a watch?
Yes.
How much time will it take?
I don't know.
Maybe...
Four or five years.
Five years, it is.
You know, I
used to call this
a symbol of excellence.
Actually, it's a symbol
of their arrogance.
The Swiss watchmakers
don't consider Indians
good enough to collaborate with.
No problem.
We will make watches
without collaborating with them.
I want the finest watch
in the world,
entirely made in India, in my hand.
Until then,
I will not wear a watch.
Good luck!